<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unemployment | Gilbert Fontana</title>
    <link>https://gilbertfontana.github.io/tag/unemployment/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gilbertfontana.github.io/tag/unemployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Unemployment</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gilbertfontana.github.io/media/icon_hub5dc27100c18eb2b27a60957df55d979_236085_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Unemployment</title>
      <link>https://gilbertfontana.github.io/tag/unemployment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employment and the business cycle</title>
      <link>https://gilbertfontana.github.io/post/blog1/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gilbertfontana.github.io/post/blog1/blog1/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Inflation has increase rapidly in many developed countries during the latest months. Surging energy prices as a result of the Russo-Ukrainian War and supply chains distortions as a consequence of the pandemic are the main forces which contribute to the recent increase in the prices of goods and services. The reduced purchasing power decrease the aggregated demand and the probability of recession are increasing in many countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short-term fluctuations in the the economy is often referred to as business cycles. These cycles are typically measured by examining changes and variation in macroeconomic variables such as GDP, consumer confident indices and employment. In this blog post I will try to explain how business cycles and employment are related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employment is typically considered a lagging indicator of the business cycle. A lagging indicator generally change after the overall economy as whole does. Employment is strongly pro-cyclical and employment series lag the business cycle by approximately one quarter (Stock &amp;amp; Watson, 1999).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;references&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock, J. H., &amp;amp; Watson, M. W. (1999). Business cycle fluctuations in US macroeconomic time series. Handbook of macroeconomics, 1, 3-64.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
